准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
蟹黄堡好朋友
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
好吃
Delicious
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
嗨  珊迪
Hi, Sandy
你能顺带过来真是好
Nice of ya to drop in
来看看
Check it out
我做了一样新发明
I science'd up a new invention
叫做人格赋予机
I call it the Anthropomorphizer
我来为你演示
Allow me to demonstrate
调料
Seasoning
快看
Voila
速成生命
Instant life
谢谢
Thank you
珊迪  这真能让东西活起来吗
Sandy, can it really bring anything to life?
你可以赌一把
You can bet the farm on it
连蟹黄堡都能活吗
Even a krabby patty?
对
Yep
肯定行
I reckon so
上菜了
Order up
活过来了
It lives
我的蟹黄堡活过来了
My Krabby Patty lives
天啊  好怪的感觉
My, what odd sensations
感觉好像
I feel like--
好像能感觉了一样
well, like I can feel
这就是活过来
That's called livin'
你可以走路  可以说话
You can walk and talk
想必你也满面包经纶吧
and I reckon you got a few thoughts up in the ol' bun too
确实
I reckon I do
不敢相信
I can't believe it
真的会有蟹黄堡可以说话
A real krabby patty who can talk
还可以让我回话
and I can talk back to it
还可以谈论心中所爱
and we can talk about everything we love
毕竟我从来不知道蟹黄堡爱什么
because I never knew what krabby patties loved
但现在我可以知道了
but now I can know
而且它还可以知道我知道的东西
and it can know what I know
因为我爱蟹黄堡
because I know I love krabby patties
我可以带你看我在裤头村的心中所爱
and I can show you what I love in Bikini Bottom
那就加倍奶酪了
Well, double my cheese
这就跟你走
I'm in
我为快餐赋予了生命
Welp, I've created life from nothing but fast food
想必我是全世界最聪明的松鼠了
I reckon I'm the smartest squirrel in the world
水母田
这是水母田
This is Jellyfish Fields
我跟我朋友就来这捉水母
It's where my friends and I go jellyfishing
什么
What the?
特别是你这样的新朋友
Especially new friends like you
快看  蟹黄堡
And look, Krabby Patty
我还多带了一个小网
I even brought an extra little net
方便你来学
so you can learn how to--
你捉到我了
You caught me
快扔了
Drop it
那肮脏的汉堡来路不明
You don't know where that nasty patty's been
那肮脏的汉堡是我朋友
That nasty Krabby Patty is my friend
要多加小心  蟹黄堡
You need to be more careful, Krabby Patty
你就是忍不住会好吃
You can't help it that you're delicious
高菲高伯
这里是高菲高伯
This is Goofy Goober's
全裤头村最美味的冰淇淋店
the tastiest ice cream joint in town
大家表情都好快乐
Everyone looks so happy
我也想跟他们一样快乐  海绵宝宝
I want to be happy like them, SpongeBob
我是高菲高伯耶
I'm a Goofy Goober yeah
你是高菲高伯耶
you're a Goofy Goober, yeah
好先生
Good sir
来个两人份的最快乐的高伯莓黎明
Your happiest Gooberberry Sunrise for two
是要我们两个分着吃吗
Sharing with ourselves today, are we?
不对  我要跟我的新朋友分
No, I'm sharing with my new friend
蟹黄堡
Krabby Patty
我来救你
I'll save you
蟹黄堡  我们还是快走吧
Come on, Krabby Patty, we're leaving
我再也不会回来
And I am never coming back to
这个吃顾客的地方了
a place that would eat a customer
好  明天再见
K, see you tomorrow
真抱歉大家都要来吃你  蟹黄堡
I'm sorry everyone keeps trying to eat you, Krabby Patty
你这一生应该就今天最惨了
You must be having the worst day of your life
不得不说
I've gotta say
我并非那么想
it hasn't been what I thought
无论我跳进别人的嘴里多少次
No matter how many times I jump in someone's mouth
他们还是不愿意吞了我
they still won't swallow me
等等
Wait
你是故意要跳进别人嘴里的吗
you were jumping into their mouths on purpose?
那当然了
Of course
大家不是都想让别人吃吗
Doesn't everyone want to be eaten?
才不是
No way
起码我不想
At least I don't think so
我想让别人吃我
Well, I want to be eaten
并且我现在就要让别人吃
and I want to be eaten now
等等  别
Wait, no
不行
You can't
我可以
Yes I can
托儿所
蟹黄堡  快回来
Krabby Patty, come back
看过来  小朋友
Over here, kids
你们已经可以吃固体食物了
I think you're ready for solid foods
我不会让你滴上他们的口水
I won't let them slobber on you
走开  小朋友
Move it, moppet
跑远点  小孩子
Scram, squirt
我的宝贝
My babies
蟹黄堡  快回来
Patty, come back
海之霸
要是蟹黄堡到不了我手上
Well, if I can't get my hands on a krabby patty
起码我还能圆梦去滑一场雪
then at least I can go on that ski trip I always wanted
别管了
Never mind
傻子才滑雪
Skiing is for jerks
蟹黄堡  快过来
Hey, krabby patty, over here
我想要的聊天对象就是
I'd like to have a word with
你
you?
吃我
Eat me
一定要塞进去
I've gotta fit in here
加把劲
Come on
找到你了
There you are
抱歉  痞老板
Sorry, Plankton
蟹黄堡他非常想要让
Krabby Patty here thinks that he wants to--
快走开
Go away
我想一个人静静
I need to be alone
我不明白  蟹黄堡
I don't get it, Krabby Patty
你难道就不想陪着我  当好朋友呢
Don't you want to stay with me and be my friend?
我当然想了  海绵宝宝
Of course I do, SpongeBob
可是捉水母和冰淇淋
But jellyfishing and ice cream
只适合你这样的人
well, they're for people like you
我不一样
I'm different
就好像你让别人快乐的办法
It's like how your purpose is making people happy
就是给大家吃的
by feeding them
我让别人快乐的办法
my purpose is making people happy
就是让大家吃我
by feeding them me
知道吗  蟹黄堡
You know what, Krabby Patty?
我现在明白了
I get it now
我要协助你
And I'm going to help you
变成最棒的一餐
be the best meal you can be
一起去找最完美的嘴巴来吃掉你吧
Let's find the perfect mouth to gobble you up
我好快乐
I'm one happy patty
吃我
观众们可以进来吃我的蟹黄堡好朋友了
Auditions are now open to eat my friend Patty
下一位
Next, please
只有我才会细细品鉴蟹黄堡
Only I know how to truly savor a krabby patty
因此  我认为我应该具有
Therefore, I believe I should have
可以把你吃了的完美特质
the distinction of eating you
你上一餐品鉴的貌似有点久了
I think you savored that last one a little too long
下一位
Next
真想不到
Well, I never
看起来好好吃的小人儿
What a delicious-looking little man
我可以嚼你好几个小时
I could chew on you for hours
对
Yeah
你嘴巴好像已经塞满东西了  先生
I think your mouth is already occupied, mister
下一位
Next
你们好
Howdy--
为什么闷闷不乐
Why the long faces?
可真是黄瓜薯片
Pickle chips
我只想让别人吃我而已
All I want is to be eaten
可就是没法找到完美的嘴巴
But we just can't find the perfect mouth
那
Well
也许海绵宝宝比较适合把你吃了
Maybe SpongeBob could give you the ol' bite and chew
牙口好
Great teeth
舌头健康
healthy tongue
口气清新
Minty-fresh breath
抹番茄酱啊  找到完美的嘴巴了
Spread my ketchup, the perfect mouth
真是我莫大的荣幸  海绵宝宝
It would be an honor, SpongeBob
不  蟹黄堡
Oh, no, Krabby Patty
应该是我荣幸才对
The honor is mine
用餐愉快  朋友
Bon appétit, friend
住口
Halt
蟹黄堡得给我
I deserve this patty
很明显我才最饿
I'm clearly the hungriest
大家都是为了渺小的我
All this for little old me
又何必要告诉我呢
Why if you'd told me
我原本只是无生命的配料
when I was a lifeless pile of ingredients
某天突然
that someday I'd
看来蟹黄堡的心愿达成了
Welp, I guess it got what it wanted
所以小蜗  好不好吃
So, Gary, how was it?
站住
Halt
都是这松鼠害大家打起来的
I blame the squirrel for this fracas
她诱使我们互相攻击
She made us turn on each other
手上的邪恶科学害人不浅
with her wicked, wicked science
科学就是会有得必有失
Well, science giveth, and science taketh away
带我走吧  科学
Take me away, science
乐得不可思议
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
现在播出的是电视评论
And now with an editorial
全员糟糕透顶
有请章鱼哥
here's Squidward Tentacles
晚上好
Good evening
所有人持续不断糟糕透顶
Everyone continues to be horrible
由我为大家证明
and I've got the proof
下面是我的  每周怨言
Here are my "Beefs of the week"
第一条怨言
Our first beef is
这位肮脏美食家老是先吃后付款
this filthy foodie always eats before he pays
吃完了就手捧纸钞给我
Then he gives me a handful of money
纸钞上面涂满了黏糊糊的油
slathered in slimy grease
暂停
糟糕透顶
Horrible
下一条
Next
我对这位烦人精有着十足的怨言
Boy, do I have a beef with this annoying guy
什么
What?
播完了
I'm done?
可我还有47条怨言
But I've got 47 more "beefs"
果不其然
Typical
接下来播出的是  乐得不可思议
Coming up next, it's "Fun-believable"
主持人是
with
金鱼鲁布
Rube Goldfish?
不行
Oh, no
那位还喝奶昔还加芥末酱
That guy puts mustard in his milkshakes
糟糕透顶
Horrible
小心点
Watch it
大家好啊
Well, hello, everybody
我是金鱼鲁布
I'm Rube Goldfish
今天我们将要探索
and today we'll be exploring
神奇又未知的裤头村
the amazing and unknown Bikini Bottom
乐得不可思议
金鱼鲁布领衔主演
警告
Warning
你们即将会看到的事物
what you are about to see
绝对能让你们说出  乐得不可思议
is gonna make you say, "That's Fun-believable"
小餐馆
荫凉滩疗养院
厨师博物馆
我们到了珊迪的树屋
We're here at Sandy Cheeks' Treedome
因为
because--
不好意思  鲁布
Excuse us, Rube, but
公厕就在这附近  你们两个
The public restroom is right around the corner, boys
不对  我跟派大星有东西要给你看
No, Patrick and I have something to show you
乐得不可思议
It's "Fun-believable"
真的吗
Really?
我一直很想找呢
Well, that's just what I'm looking for
秀出你们的本领
Show us what you got
好  准备好了吗
Okay, you ready?
好了
I think so
我们的机会来了
This is our chance
不必直接说出来  海绵宝宝
You don't have to tell me, SpongeBob
好了
All right
他还在吗
Is he still there?
去看一下
Let's check
好  他还在
Okay, he's still there
准备好了吗
You ready?
好了
Yeah
一  二
One, two
我们准备好了
We're ready
我们没准备好
We're not ready
好  等准备好了再回来
Okay, come back when you are
一定是不好意思上镜了
Must be camera shy
快看看啊
Would you look at that?
太神了
Amazing
你好啊  鲁布
Howdy do, Rube?
你好  珊迪小姐
Howdy, Miss Cheeks
这机械臂感觉不是很乐得不可思议
Now, if the robotic arms weren't "Fun-believable" enough
想必你有什么不为人知的秘密技能吧
I understand that you have a secret skill
that nobody knows about
没错  鲁布
That's right, Rube
我保持着嘴含最多坚果的松鼠记录
I hold the squirrel record
for the most nuts stored in my cheeks
可以给大家演示一下吗
Can you give us a demonstration?
当然可以了
Sure can
我刚好准备了一点榛子
I just happened to have some hazelnuts handy
惊为天人
Impressive
好像已经没办法另外多塞点坚果了
I don't think it's possible to fit any more than that
好戏还没上场呢
You ain't seen nuttin' yet
乐得不可思议
Fun-believable
鲁布
Oh, Rube?
我们准备好了
We're ready
各位观众  看来
Well, folks, it looks like--
我坚果吃得肚子疼
I think I have a nut-ache
抱歉  珊迪
Sorry, Sandy
鲁布  得等会儿再回来吗
Hey, Rube, should we come back later?
好  等会儿就等会儿
Yeah, later would be good
我们来到了诺斯费拉图的古堡
We're here at Nosferatu's Castle
这里也是裤头村的一座历史地标
Which is a Historical landmark
in Bikini Bottom, by the way
谢谢你  鲁布
Well, thanks, Rube
我们今天缘何而来  诺斯费拉图先生
But why are we here today, Mr. Nosferatu?
能给我们提示一下吗
Could you give us a hint?
主人想要向你们展示他的
The master wants to show you his--
殓锁反应
pain-reaction--
我是说  连锁反应机
I mean chain-reaction machine
这个怪异机器的工作原理是什么
So how does this crazy contraption work, anyway?
好的  主人
Okay, Master
启动
let it roll
天啊
Oh, my
点心
Snackies
泡牙
主人说
The master says
鲁布的节目由泡牙汽水赞助播出
Rube's show is brought to you by Fizzy Fangs Soda
让我牙齿好痒
It tickles my teeth
真是太乐得不可思议了
Fellas, that was truly Fun-believable
我们准备好了  鲁布
We're ready for you, Rube
确定吗
Are you sure?
没好
No
属于他们的时代大概已经离去
I guess their moment has passed
世了
away
现在采访的是梅干宝宝
We're here with "Baby Prunes"
你现在是全裤头村最老的居民
Now, you're the oldest resident of Bikini Bottom
对不对啊
Isn't that right?
你干什么的  警察吗
What are you, a cop?
妈  表现好点
Ma, behave
他在采访我  玛丽
He's interviewing me, Mary
给我闭嘴
so shut up
你也太夸张了
You are too much
亲爱的  你早该在七十年前看到我
Honey, you should have seen me 70 years ago
鱼到中年还放荡不羁的样子
when I was middle-aged and wild
开什么玩笑呢
You're putting me on
你这么一个可爱的小老太太怎么会
How could a sweet little old lady like you
放荡不羁呢
ever be wild?
有人给我立下挑战了
That sounds like a challenge
我的直升机啊
Holy helicopters
我们现在正飞行在裤头村上空
We are flying over Bikini Bottom
景观尤为壮丽
and the view is spectacular
大家好
Hello
嗨  鲁布
Hi, Rube
梅干宝宝
Baby Prunes
我从来没见过像你这么大年纪
I've never seen someone your age
还这么活蹦乱跳的
so amazingly active
这还叫活蹦乱跳
You call this active?
给你见识一下活蹦乱跳
I'll show you active
梅干太太  可以不用开这么快
Mrs. Prunes, you don't have to go this fast
让我大开眼界
to impress me
我是你的机长
This is your captain speaking
马上又要下降了
We're going down again
刚刚已经远远不止乐得不可思议了
That was the furthest thing from Fun-believable
差点就让你骗了
You could have fooled me
正前方有会飞的吵东西
Flapping Yaps at 12:00
本次千船相撞事故
This thousand-boat pileup
可能是全裤头村发生的最惨烈悲剧
might be the greatest tragedy
to ever befall Bikini Bottom
我想感谢我的太奶奶
And I just want to thank my Great Gram-Gram
今天来驾驶直升机
for flying the copter today
她全裤头村年龄最老  有115岁
She is the oldest citizen in Bikini Bottom at 115
你在裤头村才不是最老
You are not the oldest citizen in Bikini Bottom
你才115岁
You're only 115
我116岁
I'm 116
你骗人
You fibber
要是我没你老
If I wasn't your elder
我就用拳头呼你鼻子
I'd pop you right in the beezer
我最老
I'm the oldest
我要挑战你  来场直升机决斗
I challenge you to a copter duel
开斗吧  跟我助听器一样开
It's on, like my hearing aid
直升机决斗
Copter duel?
不
No
刚刚收到的消息
This just in
新闻频道主持人帕奇帕金斯
TV news anchor Perch Perkins
今天跳下了一架直升机
jumped out of a helicopter today
这里可是禁飞区  姐妹
This is a no-fly zone, sister
我说你
Hey, you
从我的云上下去
Get off of my cloud
我最老
I'm the oldest
我必须把这档节目的名字
I'll have to change the name of this show
从乐得不可思议  改成
from "FUN-believable" to
啊
ahhh
手套乐园
该回家了  你们两个
Time to go home, you two
是啊  刺激的事就点到为止吧
Yeah, that's enough excitement for today
我最老
I'm the oldest
我才最老
I am the oldest
我最老
I'm the oldest
看来她确实最老
I guess she was the oldest
出口
但我现在最老了
But I'm the oldest now
我们的节目就要告一段落了
Well, we've come to end of our show, everybody
我想告诉大家  有多么乐得
and I just want to tell ya how Fun-be--
我们准备好了  鲁布
We're ready, Rube
再不做就来不及了
It's now or never, fellas
开始你们的表演
Take it away
哒哒
Ta-da
乐得不可思议
真是乐得不可思议
Now, that's Fun-believable
糟糕透顶
Horrible
我按
Click